The family just got a little stranger.
Addams Family Values is a comedy, family, fantasy
film directed by Barry Sonnenfeld.
Siblings Wednesday and Pugsley Addams will stop at nothing to get rid of
Pubert, the new baby boy adored by parents Gomez and Morticia.
Things go from bad to worse when the new "black widow" nanny, Debbie Jellinsky,
launches her plan to add Fester to her collection of dead husbands.
Morticia Addams, played by Anjelica Huston.
Gomez Addams, played by Raúl Juliá.
Uncle Fester, played by Christopher Lloyd.
Debbie Jellinsky, played by Joan Cusack.
Wednesday Addams, played by Christina Ricci.
Granny, played by Carol Kane.
Addams Family Values is a 1993 American black comedy film, based on
the comic strip characters created by Charles Addams.
It is the sequel to The Addams Family (1991).
Directed by Barry Sonnenfeld and written by Paul Rudnick, the film features most of the cast members from the original film, including
Anjelica Huston, Raul Julia, Christopher Lloyd and Christina Ricci, with Joan Cusack and Carol Kane joining the cast.
Compared to its predecessor, which retained something of the madcap approach of the 1960s
sitcom, Addams Family Values is played more for dark and macabre laughs.
The film revolves around the family's adjustments
to the birth of new baby Pubert.
Subplots include Uncle Fester marrying the new nanny Debbie Jellinsky, who is a serial killer intending to murder
him for his inheritance; and teenagers Wednesday and Pugsley Addams being sent to summer camp.
Addams Family Values was released in the United States on
November 19, 1993, by Paramount Pictures.
In contrast to its predecessor's mixed reception, the film was well received by critics but it was not as
financially successful, with a box office gross of $111 million against a budget of $47 million.
In the decades since its release, the film has become
acclaimed for its humor and performances.
The film was followed by a further sequel, Addams Family Reunion.
The film explores themes of dancing, jealousy, baby,
sibling relationship, summer camp.
The tone is lighthearted.